I can't believe we've never done this. It's so good!
我們居然沒試過 真舒服
It's so good for Monica.
摩妮卡好舒服
Time's up! My turn.
時間到，該我了
-That was half an hour? -It's your timer.
已經半小時了？ 計時器是你的
I don't like to brag about it, but I give the best massages.
我不想自誇，但我最會按摩了
All right,then massage me up right nice!
那就給我按下去吧
It's so good,isn't it?
很舒服吧？
I don't know what I did to deserve it.
舒服到我覺得我無福消受
Now stop trying to add more time to your massage.
別想把時間延長
Say goodbye to sore muscles!
跟酸痛肌肉說再見吧
Goodbye,muscles!
肌肉，再見
The One with Joey's Bag
本集播出：「父女相認」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
She gives the worst massages ever!
她的按摩技術爛到不行
It was like she was torturing me for information.
感覺就像她在拷問我
I wanted to give it up. I just didn't know what it was!
我很想招，又不知道要招什麼
If it hurts that bad, you should tell her.
要是真的很痛，你應該告訴她
For the first time, I'm in a real relationship.
我這輩子第一次這麼認真
I won't screw that up by telling the truth.
我才不要因為說實話而搞砸
Dude,look out!
小心
You almost crushed my hat.
你差點踩扁我的帽子
Sorry.
對不起
And the bunny got away.
兔子跑走了
This would be the place where you explain the hat.
你該解釋這頂帽子的事了
This is called a top hat.
這個叫禮帽
And why are you wearing this? Is it "top hat"?
你為何要戴這頂…禮帽是吧？
There's this play...
現在有一出舞台劇
...and I'm up for the part of this cool, suave, international guy.
我要去應徵一個很有品位的角色
A clotheshorse. So I figure...
他很會穿衣服 我估計...
...everyone at the audition will wear ultra-hip,high-fashion stuff.
...去試鏡的人 一定都會穿得很時尚有品位
And you'll make them disappear?
你要把他們都變不見？
Like you could find something this sophisticated.
有什麼比這頂帽子更有品？
Done!
搞定
If you want to look good, come to the store. I'll help you.
喬伊，你可以來找我選衣服
-Thanks! -Sure.
太好了，謝謝
Please, take those off!
不客氣…拜託快拿掉
Hey,Phoebe. How's it going?
菲比，今天好嗎？
Only okay because I just got back from the hospital.
還好而已，因為我剛去過醫院
Are you all right?
什麼？ 你還好嗎？
I'm fine, but my grandma sort of died.
不，我很好，但是我外婆死了
Phoebe,sorry.
真遺憾
It's okay.
沒關係
She had a really incredible life.
她這一生過得很精彩
It's not like I won't see her again. She'll visit.
我也不是永遠見不到她 她會來找我
Maybe she's with us right now.
也許她現在就在這裡？
Right. She's on a new spiritual plain and she'll come to the coffeehouse.
是啊，第一天進入新世界 結果跑來咖啡館
I just saw two people having sex in a car right outside!
喂！外面車上有兩個人在嘿咻
Phoebe' grandmother just died.
菲比的外婆剛過世
Oh,my God! I'm so sorry.
天哪，對不起
Actually, it's kind of cool. Because it's like...
沒關係，其實這樣還蠻酷的
...you know,one life ends and another begins.
一個生命結束 另一個生命誕生
Not the way they're doing it.
他們的做法很難
What happened? How did she die?
怎麼回事？她是怎麼過世的？
We were in the market...
我們在超市...
...and she bent down to get some yogurt and never came back up again.
她彎腰去拿優格 就再也沒起來過
I'm so sorry.
真令人遺憾
The last thing she said was:
她最後說的話倒很窩心
"You get the eggs, I'll get the yogurt, and we'll meet at the checkout counter."
「你去拿蛋，我拿優格」 「我們在出口見」
You know what?
你們知道嗎？
We will meet at the checkout counter.
我們絕對會在人生的出口見
（布魯明戴爾百貨公司）
Since you're returning all this stuff...
衣服得歸還
...you'll have to wear underwear.
所以你得穿內褲
All right. You'd better show me that too.
好，那你還得拿內褲給我
It's missing something.
還少了點什麼…
Really? A purse?
我知道了 皮包喔？
It's not a purse. It's a shoulder bag.
這不是皮包，是背包
It looks like a woman's purse.
很像女人的皮包
Trust me, all the men are carrying them in the spring catalog.
不，相信我 春季型錄上的男模都在背
See,look. Men carrying the bag.
你看，男人，背包包
See,look. Women carrying the bag.
你看，女人，背包包
But it is odd how a woman's purse looks so good on me, a man.
我一個男人背女用皮包 居然很帥
Exactly. Unisex!
沒錯，男女通用 （音同「你需要性愛」）
Maybe you need sex. I had sex a couple days ago.
你或許需要，我2天前剛做過
No,Joey. U-N-I sex.
不，我是說男女通用 （音同「你和我做愛」）
I ain't gonna say no to that!
我絕對不會拒絕
-Who is it? -It's Phoebe.
哪一位？ 菲比
Oh,great!
太好了
Oh,you.
原來是你…
What's up?
有什麼事？
Well,I sort of have some bad news. Can I come in?
有個壞消息，我可以進去嗎？
No,thanks.
還是不要好了
Grandma died today.
外婆今天死了
Didn't she die like five years ago?
她不是5年前就死了？
No,she just died today.
不是，她今天剛死
We're having a memorial service tomorrow.
明天要舉行告別式
Okay,I know I went to that already.
我參加過她的告別式了
No,you didn't!
你才沒有
Then who's been dead?
那是誰死了5年？
Lots of people!
很多人
-Look,are you coming or not? -No.
你到底要不要來？ 不要
I thought she was dead, so I've made my peace.
我以為她已經死了 我已經接受這件事了
Plus I'm going to a concert.
而且我明天要聽演唱會
I'd invite you, but I only have two tickets left.
我也想找你，但我只剩兩張票
-Fine. Okay,enjoy your concert. -Thanks. Enjoy your funeral!
好，你慢慢聽 謝了，你慢慢告別
You look just like your son, Mrs. Tribbiani.
崔比亞尼太太 你長得真像你兒子
What? Are you referring to my man's bag?
什麼？你在說我的男用包包？
I thought it just looked good, but it's practical too.
我原以為它只中看 結果它也很中用，你們看
It's got compartments for your wallet,keys,address book....
各種夾層都有 放皮夾的 放鑰匙的 放電話簿的
Your makeup.
放化妝品的
What are you doing? The audition's tomorrow.
喬伊，你怎麼背著包包？ 你明天才試鏡
Yeah,but sandwich time is right now.
但現在是三明治時間
You get mustard on that bag, you can't return it.
要是沾到芥末就不能還了
Why would I return this? I love this bag!
幹嘛要還？我愛這個包包
-All right,then you owe me $350. -Fine.
好，那你欠我350  好
Do you take Vasa or Mooster Card?
你收VASA或萬事達嗎
Relax,I'll pay you with the money from the job I'll get. Thanks to you.
別緊張啦 你幫我拿到這個角色 到時領了錢就給你
What's the part? Auntie Mame?
什麼角色，反男人？
Don't listen to them. I think it's sexy.
別理他們，我覺得很性感
You-and-I sexy?
你和我，性感？
Hello,Mrs. Pinilla. Thank you for coming.
潘奈拉太太，謝謝你來
Here's your 3-D glasses.
這是你的3D眼鏡
Reverend Pong will say when to put them on.
要戴時彭牧師會說
Hi,sweetie.
嗨，親愛的
-How are you holding up? -Fine.
你還好嗎？ 還好
Hey,Phoebe. I'm so sorry.
節哀順變
You know what? My grandma had the exact same bag!
我外婆有個一模一樣的包包
I brought you flowers.
我帶了花來
Oh,thanks!
謝謝
Pulling flowers out makes the bag look masculine.
這樣感覺有男人味多了
Excuse me,is this the memorial?
請問告別式是在這裡嗎？
Yeah.Welcome. Hello.
對，歡迎 你好
Here's your 3-D glasses.
這是你的3D眼鏡
Thanks. All right.
謝謝，好
So how did you know Frances?
你是怎麼認識法蘭西絲的？
Actually,I hadn't seen her for years.
我們多年不見
But I was pretty tight with her and her daughter.
我以前跟她和她的女兒很親
What's your name?
是嗎？尊姓大名？
Frank Buffay.
法蘭克布非
You know what? Strike that. My name,actually,is Joe.
更正，其實我叫…喬
Joe Hill.
喬希爾
You're Frank Buf
你是法蘭克布非？
No! Joe Hill.
不是，喬希爾
You just said
你剛才說…
I got to go. Thank you so much for coming.
我該走了，謝謝你來
But...
但是…
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
What happened?
什麼？ 怎麼了？
That was my dad.
那是我爸 天哪
Check it out!
你們看
It's like it's coming right at me.
我的手好像正朝著我來
-Did you catch him? -What did he say?
追到他了嗎？ 他怎麼說？
He said, "Nice to meet you,Glenda."
他說：很高興認識你，葛蘭達
I couldn't give him my real name.
我當然不能說出真名
Why not?
為什麼？
You saw the way he ran.
你們也看到他走得像飛了
You think he'd talk to the daughter he abandoned?
難不成他會留下來 跟他拋棄的女兒聊天？
What did you say to him?
那你怎麼說？
I said I was the executor of the will and I needed to talk to him.
我自稱法蘭西絲的遺囑執行人 有事找他談
I'm going to meet him at the coffeehouse.
我們待會約在咖啡館
Could everyone take their seats?
請各位就座
I just can't think about that now.
我現在沒辦法想這個
I want to say goodbye to my grandma.
我只想跟我外婆道別 好
Let's go say goodbye.
走吧
I'm off to my audition. How do I look?
我要去面試了，怎麼樣？
Great! That bag will get you that part.
帥呆了，那個包包會讓你包中
And a date with a man.
還能釣到男人
You know what? Make fun all you want. This is a great bag.
隨你怎麼取笑我 這個包包很棒
And it's as handy as it is becoming.
而且是好看又好用
Just because you don't understand something, doesn't make it wrong.
你們不懂不代表是錯的
You guys have to get used to the fact that Joey...
以後你們都得習慣有喬伊…
...comes with a bag!
就有包包
I've got to meet my dad.
我也該走了，我得去見我爸
Will you tell him who you are?
你會表明你的身份嗎？
Not at first. I don't want to freak him out.
先不會，我不想嚇跑他
But aren't you pissed at him?
但是你不氣他嗎？
This guy abandoned you.
這傢伙遺棄了你
If it were me, this guy would be in some serious physical danger.
如果是我，他就等著挨揍吧
I'd walk in there, I'd be like, "Yo,Dad!
我會走進去說 「喂，老爸」
You and me,outside. Right now!"
「我們現在就出去解決」
I kind of scared myself.
我都嚇到自己了
Well,at least you scared someone.
那起碼有嚇到人
You'd think I'd be angry.
說也奇怪，我應該很生氣
You'd think I'd want to rip his tiny, little head off!
我應該很想扭斷他那顆頭
Fortunately, I'm past it.
幸好我已經釋懷了
You do seem a little tense. Here,let me help you.
你看起來的確有點緊繃 我幫你捏一捏 好
Get off!
放開我！
Stop it! Why are you doing that to me?
住手！你為什麼這樣苦毒我？
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
As a masseuse and a human...
身為一個按摩師和一個人類
...I'm begging you, never do that to anyone!
我懇求你永遠別幫別人按摩
I give good massages.
我很會按摩啊
I gave them to Rachel before she got allergic.
我以前都幫瑞秋按摩 是她後來會過敏
And Chandler, he loves them! Watch.
錢德也很喜歡，你看
He does not like it. He's in pain!
他才不喜歡，他痛得快要死了
-No,he's not. -Yes,he is!
他才沒有 他有
-What? -I'm sorry,but
什麼？ 對不起，但是…
You've been lying to me?
你一直在騙我？
I can't believe that.
我真不敢相信
Maybe he didn't want to hurt you.
也許他只是不希望你難過
But the minute we start to lie to each other....
但我們一旦開始欺騙對方…
And by "we"...
我說的「我們」...
...I mean society.
...指的是社會
Anytime you're ready.
你好了就開始
Well,you must be new here.
你一定是新來的
Maybe we get a table, I buy you a drink.
我們找張桌子，我請你喝一杯
Could you try it without the purse?
抱歉，你能不能不要背皮包？
Yeah,sure.
當然可以
Well,you must be new here. Maybe we sit
你一定是新來的 我們找張…
Can I ask you something?
抱歉，我可以問一件事嗎？
Sure. What?
可以，什麼事？
Well,first, it's not a purse.
第一，這不是皮包
Anytime.
好，再來
If you think it's a woman's bag,it's not.
別以為這是女用皮包
It's a man's bag.
這是男用提包
Okay. And go!
好的，繼續吧
Let me show you the catalog.
我拿型錄給你看
Look. See?
你看
It's the latest thing.
這是最新流行
Everyone's got one. Men,women,children.
男人、女人、小孩都在背
Do you sell these?
你在推銷這些包包嗎？
No,these babies sell themselves.
不是，這些包包擺著就能賣
Thank you. That was great.
好，謝謝，你表現得很好
But I didn't read anything.
我什麼都還沒念
I think we've seen enough.
我想這樣就夠了
All right,I'll see you.
那好，再見
We got it. We got it.
搞定了，搞定了
-Is Rachel here? -No.
瑞秋在嗎？ 不在
Listen, I just wanted to apologize about the whole massage thing.
聽我說 我想為下午和按摩的事道歉
I really like them.
我很喜歡你的按摩
Please,stop!
別再硬撐了
We're supposed to be honest.
我們應該坦誠相對
I wish you could tell me, "l don't like your massages."
我只希望你能明白告訴我 「我不喜歡你的按摩」
I don't like your massages.
我不喜歡你的按摩
See? It's no big deal.
看吧，又沒什麼
But now you're crying!
但是你哭了
I'm not crying about that. I'm crying about something at work.
我不是在哭這個 我是在哭公司的事
-What? -My boyfriend said he didn't like my massages.
什麼事？ 我男朋友說他不喜歡我的按摩
You don't have to be best at everything.
你又不必事事都搶第一
Oh,my God! You don't know me at all!
天哪，你一點也不暸解我
You give the worst massages in the world.
好，你的按摩技術天下第一爛
I'm crying here!
我在哭耶
Look,hear me out.
聽我說完
You give the best bad-massages.
比爛的話你天下第一
If anybody was looking for the best bad-massage...
如果有人在找最棒的爛按摩
...and they thought, "Who's the best?"
他們自問：誰的爛技術最棒？
They'd have to go to you.
那絕對非你莫屬
So you're saying that if there was an award...
你的意思是 如果有...
...for the best bad-massage.... Who would get that?
...最佳爛按摩技術獎 那誰會得獎？
It would be you!
一定是你
You,Monica! And you'd get all the votes.
你，摩妮卡 你會大獲全勝
So they could call the award, "The Monica"?
或許這個獎可以叫摩妮卡獎？
Absolutely.
一定會的
-I suck! -Yeah.
我爛透了 沒錯
Thank you for meeting me.
謝謝你來見我
Thank you.
謝謝
Come sit.
這邊坐
Sit.
坐啊
Sit!
坐
Alrighty. Before we get started,I need you...
好的，在開始之前
...to state for the record that you are,in fact,Frank Buffay.
你必須鄭重聲明 你其實是法蘭克布非
Yes,I am.
是的，我是
What did Frances leave me?
法蘭西絲留給我什麼？
That's why you wanted me to come.
這是你找我來的原因吧？
Yes,she did. She left you...
是的 的確有，她留給你…
...this lipstick.
這支口紅
這真是…
It's used.
這是用過的
Cool!
酷
I have just a few questions to ask, so I'll get out my official forms.
我要請教幾個問題 我把相關表格拿出來
Okay. So question one:
好，第一個問題
You were married to Frances' daughter,Lilly. Correct?
你娶了法蘭西絲的女兒莉莉 正不正確？
Yes,I was.
對，沒錯
Question two. Did that marriage end:
好，第二個問題 這段婚姻
A: Happily?
一：很美滿
B: Medium?
二：普通
Or C: In the total abandonment...
三：你最後...
...of her and her two children?
...拋妻棄子
It really says that?
表上真的這麼寫？
Yeah,see?
對，你看
I guess then I would have to say C.
那我就得選三了
Total abandonment.
好，拋妻棄子
Reasons for abandonment:
拋棄的原因
A: Top-secret government work.
一：極機密政府工作
B: Amnesia.
二：失意症
Or C: You're just a selfish, irresponsible...
或是三 你就是個自私不負責的...
...bad,bad man.
大壞蛋
I don't want the lipstick that much.
其實我沒那麼想要這支口紅
Would you do me a favor?
請你幫個忙
Would you give Lilly...
把這個交給莉莉
...that,please? -What?
拜託. 什麼？
When you see Lilly, give her that note.
請把那張紙條交給她
I wanted to talk to her at the memorial...
我本來想在告別式上找她談
...but I pictured her getting mad the way you did,and I chickened out.
但我覺得她也會像你這樣發飆 就臨陣退縮了
I wrote her a note. Give it to her,please?
我寫了那張紙條，請幫我轉交
But you came to see Lilly?
你想來找莉莉？
Yeah. Why?
對，怎麼了？
Lilly's dead.
莉莉死了
She what?
什麼？
She's dead.
她死了
Are you sure?
你確定？
If she isn't,cremating her was a big mistake.
沒死就被火化就嚴重了
I can't believe this. I just can't believe
我真不敢相信，怎麼會…
How? Oh,my God.
天哪， 怎麼會？
How long ago?
多久的事？
17 years ago.
17年前
What about the girls?
那女孩們呢？
Well,Ursula is a waitress and she lives in Soho.
烏蘇拉在當服務生，住在蘇活
And Phoebe...
菲比…
...is on this couch.
就坐在這張沙發上
Yep, lipstick and a daughter. Big day for you!
沒錯，口紅和女兒 真是黃道吉日
Phoebe,l....
菲比，我…
It's just,I don't know what to say.
我不知道該說什麼
I just can't believe that you're my daughter. You're so pretty.
你居然是我的女兒 你長得這麼漂亮
Yes, well, that's neither here nor there.
那個跟這個無關
Would it make you feel better if I said...
你會不會好過一點
...that I was very,very sorry I left?
如果我說我非常非常抱歉
It doesn't matter what you say. It won't make a difference.
你說什麼都沒區別了
So you can just go.
所以你可以走了
Well,you know,in my defense, I was a lousy father.
好…我要辯解一下 我很不會當爸爸
-That's your defense? -Yes,it is.
這叫辯解？ 沒錯
I burned the formula, and I put your diapers on backwards.
我把牛奶燒焦，把尿布包反
I made up a song to sing to you, but that made you cry even more.
我做了一首歌哄你睡覺 結果你哭得更厲害
You make up songs?
你會寫歌？
Well,no,just that one. But it was stupid.
只有那一首 不過很白癡
Let's see,how did it go?
我想想怎麼唱…
Sleepy girl,sleepy girl
愛困妹，愛困妹
Why won't you go to sleep?
你為什麼不睡覺？
Sleepy girl,sleepy girl
愛困妹，愛困妹
You're keeping me up
你害我不能睡覺
I'm not very good at this.
我實在…這種事我不太行
Well,I am.
我很行
Not yet. No.
現在還不行
How'd the audition go?
結果如何？
Estelle said I didn't get it.
經紀人說沒中
What? Why? Joey, you were so ready for it.
什麼？你準備得那麼充分
I thought so too...
我也這麼想
...but the casting people had problems with me.
但她說選角的人對我有意見
What kind of problem?
什麼意見？
To tell you the truth...
老實說
...they had a problem with the bag!
他們不喜歡這個包包
You know what? It was a stupid play anyway.
反正也是出爛戲
It's time to give up the bag.
喬伊，你該放棄這個包包了
I don't want to give up the bag.
我不想放棄它
I don't have to give it up. Do l,Rach?
我不必放棄它，對吧 瑞秋？
You think I should give up the bag!
你覺得我應該放棄
Joey, I'm sorry. As terrific as I think you are with it...
喬伊，對不起 我覺得你背起來很帥
...I just don't know if the world is ready for you and your bag.
但世人或許還沒辦法接受你和你的包包
I can't believe this!
你居然這麼說
Wait,I'm not saying you shouldn't have a bag.
等等，我不是說你不該帶包包
There are other bags that are maybe a little less...
但有其他爭議性比較小的...
...controversial.
...包包
Yeah,they're called wallets.
對，叫做皮夾
You're right. You're right.
你們說得對
This bag has become like a part of me.
只是它已經成為我的一部分
It's like...my bag.
它就像是…我的包包
It had a place for everything.
什麼東西都有地方擺
-Oh,man. -What?
討厭 怎麼了？
There's a whole series of pockets here I didn't even know about, Rach. Look.
有一組暗袋我沒發現啦，瑞秋
Ursula,I have the most amazing news.
烏蘇拉，我有個天大的消息
I found our dad.
我找到爸了
Phoebe.
菲比啊
Your sister. And I found our dad.
你妹妹，我找到爸了
John Glenn? John Glenn is not our dad.
約翰葛倫不是我們的爸 （著名太空人）
No,I will not join you in the lawsuit against him.
誰要跟你一起告他
It doesn't matter that he wasn't there while we were growing up.
他沒看著我們長大又怎樣
He's not our father.
他又不是我們的爸
What do you mean that's for a jury to decide?
什麼叫由陪審團決定？